Prince Boateng Asare

P. O. Box AN 18911 Accra - North

+233 26 437 0300 +233 27 768 7772

maprincegee@gmail.com

PROFILE

<u>LinkedIn</u> GitHub

PROFILE

I am a software engineer with 8 years of professional experience in software engineering, web and mobile development, information systems, and systems analysis and design.

I have the ability to examine IT systems and processes and recommend solutions.

I am a tech enthusiast, very passionate, dedicated to work to continuously develop, implement and adopt new technologies to maximize development, efficiency and produce innovative applications to solve most of the world's problems.

HIGHTLIGHTS

- Proficient in Android architecture, design and model, data structures, testing and debugging.
- Proficient in web development architectures (Model View Controller (MVC)), frameworks and technologies.
- Known for writing well documented system requirements and specifications documents.
- Known for writing efficient, maintainable and reusable code.
- Proven effective project team lead.
- Self-motivated and well-organized team player.
- Possess exemplary skills in written software development documentation.

SKILLS

Technical – HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, PHP, Java, Dart, Python, ASP.NET, Microsoft SQL, MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL.

Software – Microsoft Visio, Microsoft Project, Database Management Systems (DBMS), Version Control Systems (VCS), Collaborative tools, Android Studio, Eclipse, Visual Studio Code, Sublime Text Editor IntelliJ IDE, Postman, Insomnia.

EXPERIENCE

June 2019 - Date

WENOTEK

Senior Software Engineer

- Built Robust Application Programming Interface (APIs) for both mobile and web consumption using the Laravel framework.
- Built proof of concept minimum viable products (MVPs) using the Flutter framework.
- Trained over 300 youths into building mobile apps using the Flutter framework under the National Youth Authority (NYA) as part of the NYA Mobile App Development Training Program.
- Develop an information system software requirement specification document for developers to build new and existing solutions.

September 2017 - May 2019

Ghana India Kofi Annan Centre of Excellence in ICT

Software Developer (Research, Mobile, Web)

- Led a team to develop an Employee HR leave management system.
- Led a team that researched into a revenue collection system in Ghana.
- A member of a team that trained secondary school teachers on the use of ICT tools (chamilo, xerte) to improve the delivery of course content to students.
- A member of a team that developed on a proof of concept traffic management system.
- Managed a team of developers to work on scheduled projects and deliver within the speculated time frame.
- Researched in Bus Rapid Transport (BRT) systems and the possible solutions viable to the cities in my country (Ghana).

November, 2016 – May, 2017

Tecman Limited

Android Developer

- Designed and developed an Android news application.
- Fixed bugs and improved on application performance.
- Improved user engagement for an existing mobile application.
- Tested the application and made sure it was ready for the market.

July, 2015 – August, 2015

Rightcom Technologies

Contract Technical Writer

• I critically analysed a customer experience rating system and wrote technical documentations on it.

June, 2013 – December, 2013

Alcom Ghana

Web Developer

- Worked with a team of developers overseas on a patient-hospital management system.
- Liaison between users and overseas developers.
- Implemented Web-based project management tools to coordinate the activities of a distributed team.
- Researched and prototyped new Web technologies and techniques to realize benefits of the latest innovations, achieve increased efficiency, and provide highest quality products.

EDUCATION

May, 2018 – July, 2018

Ghana-India Kofi Annan Centre of Excellence in ICT, Ridge – Accra, Ghana **Network Information Security (NIS)**

February, 2014 – September, 2016 Staffordshire University, Stoke-on-Trent – London, England BSc. (Hons), Business Information Technology

October, 2012 – May, 2013

Ghana-India Kofi Annan Centre of Excellence in ICT, Ridge – Accra, Ghana **Diploma, Diploma in Business Computing (DBC)**

June, 2012 – September, 2012

Ghana-India Kofi Annan Centre of Excellence in ICT, Ridge – Accra, Ghana Certificate, Foundations of Software Development (FSD)